Finding Aid for the Michael D. Intriligator Papers LSC.2323
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 3: Teaching and university affairs, 1962-2012
  - Subseries 3.2: Courses., 1962-2008
    - UCLA: Economics 200., 1992-1999 (Box 70, Folder 1-7, Box 69, Folder 10)
    - UCLA: Economics 201., 1965-1974 (Box 70, Folder 8-11)
    - UCLA: Economics 203., 1988 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - UCLA: Economics 242., circa 1966-1967 (Box 71, Folder 2-5)
    - UCLA: Economics 243., 1965-1981 (Box 71, Folder 6-11)
    - UCLA: Economics 244., 1970-1978 (Box 71, Folder 12-13)
    - UCLA: Economics 245., 1969-1972 (Box 71, Folder 14-16, Box 72, Folder 1-9)
    - UCLA: Economics 246., 1978-1987 (Box 73, Folder 1-3, Box 72, Folder 10-14)
    - UCLA: Economics 248/Econometrics 2., 1975-1976 (Box 73, Folder 4-5)
    - UCLA: Economics 249., 1974 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - UCLA: Honors Collegium 190., 1982-1984 (Box 73, Folder 7-8, Box 74, Folder 1)
    - UCLA: Library reserve texts., undated (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - UCLA: PhD Economics qualifying exams., 1974-1986 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - UCLA: Policy Studies M116/Honors Collegium M119., 1999-2008 (Box 75, Folder 1-3, Box 74, Folder 4-9)
    - UCLA: Policy Studies 139., 2003 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - UCLA: Public Health/Pharmaceutical Economics and Policy., 1998-1999 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - CalTech: Economics 122 and 127., 1971 (Box 75, Folder 6-8)
    - USC: Economics courses., 1972-1973 (Box 75, Folder 9-10, Box 76, Folder 1-3)
    - USC: Economics Department administrative materials., 1972-1974 (Box 76, Folder 4-6)
    - USC: Social Science Research Institute-Public Systems Research Institute., 1972 (Box 76, Folder 7-8)
  - Subseries 3.3: Jacob Marschak Interdisciplinary Colloquium on Mathematics and Behavioral Sciences., 1962-2012
    This subseries includes materials generated from the UCLA Jacob Marschak Interdisciplinary Colloquium on Mathematics in the Behavioral Sciences. Intriligator was director of the Marschak Colloquium from 1977-1999, and co-director from 1999-2013. The materials include annual reports, program calendars, correspondence within the department, correspondence to speakers, publicity materials, presentations by Intriligator, and other administrative materials.
    - Administrative materials and correspondence., 1962-2001 (Box 77, Folder 1-7, Box 76, Folder 9-10)
    - Advisory committee., 1997-1998 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Jacob Marschak's Economic Theory of Information., 1967-1969 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Jacob Marschak memorials and reminiscences., 1978 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Speaker lists and correspondence., 1990-1999 (Box 79, Folder 1-10, Box 78, Folder 3-13)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1965-1966 (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1968-1969 (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1974-1975 (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1976-1978 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1978-1979 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1979-1980 (Box 80, Folder 3-4)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1980-1981 (Box 80, Folder 5, Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1981-1982 (Box 81, Folder 2-3)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1982-1983 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1983-1984 (Box 81, Folder 5-6)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1984-1985 (Box 82, Folder 1, Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1985-1986 (Box 82, Folder 2-3)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1986-1987 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1987-1988 (Box 82, Folder 5-6)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1988-1989 (Box 83, Folder 1-2, Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1989-1990 (Box 83, Folder 3-4)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1990-1991 (Box 83, Folder 5-6)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1991-1992 (Box 83, Folder 7-8)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1992-1993 (Box 84, Folder 1-2, Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1993-1994 (Box 84, Folder 3-4)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1994-1995 (Box 84, Folder 5-6)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1995-1996 (Box 84, Folder 7-8)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1996-1997 (Box 84, Folder 9-10)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1997-1998 (Box 85, Folder 1-4)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1998-1999 (Box 85, Folder 5-7)
    - Annual documents and reports., 1999-2000 (Box 86, Folder 1-2, Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Annual documents and reports., 2000-2001 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Annual documents and reports., 2001-2002 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Annual documents and reports., 2002-2003 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Annual documents and reports., 2003-2004 (Box 86, Folder 6-8)
    - Annual documents and reports., 2004-2005 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Annual documents and reports., 2005-2006 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Annual documents and reports., 2006-2007 (Box 87, Folder 2-3)
    - Annual documents and reports., 2007-2008 (Box 87, Folder 4-5)
    - Annual documents and reports., 2008-2009 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Annual documents and reports., 2009-2010 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Annual documents and reports., 2010-2011 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Annual documents and reports., 2011-2012 (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 3.4: Center for International and Strategic Affairs (CISA)., 1980-1994
    Intriligator was director of CISA from 1982-1992. CISA promoted the study of international security, strategy, and arms control. CISA was a predecessor to the Burkle Center for International Relations. Materials in this subseries include administrative and planning documents related to specific events, research grant documents, research and article drafts and publications.
    - Overview and administrative materials., 1980, 1992 (Box 88, Folder 1, Box 87, Folder 10-11)
    - Alcide de Gaspari Foundation., 1988 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Arms race-Disarmament., 1986-1988 (Box 88, Folder 3-5)
    - Soviet Union-Russia., 1987-1994 (Box 88, Folder 6-9, Box 89, Folder 1-2)
    - Wilton Park Joint Conference., 1989 (Box 89, Folder 3-4)
    - Pew grants., 1990-1992 (Box 89, Folder 5-6)
  - Subseries 3.5: Burkle Center for International Relations., 1998-2009
    Intriligator was director of the UCLA Burkle Center for 2000-2002. The Burkle Center fosters research on and promotes discussion of international relations, US foreign policy, and issues of global cooperation and conflict. Materials in this subseries include administrative and planning documents related to specific events, including a visit from former President Jimmy Carter.
    - Announcements, correspondence, memos and other administrative materials., 1998-2009 (Box 91, Folder 1-2, Box 90, Folder 1-5, Box 89, Folder 7-8)
    - Jimmy Carter visit speech and photographs., circa 2000 November (Box 91, Folder 3-4)
    - Kashmir Conference., 2002 (Box 91, Folder 5-6)
  - Subseries 3.6: Milken Institute., 1992-2007
    This subseries includes materials created from the Milken Institute where Intriligator was a senior fellow since 1999. He regularly wrote about and moderated panels on terrorism, Russia, and nuclear proliferation at the Milken Institute Global Conference.
    - Administrative materials., 1998-2001 (Box 91, Folder 7-8)
    - Publications., 1992-1995 (Box 91, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence., 1999-2000 (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Milken Institute Global Conference., 1999-2007 (Box 92, Folder 1-4)
- Series 4: Born-digital materials, 1997-2011
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains an unprocessed laptop, as well as born-digital files taken from Intriligator's PC hard drive, including materials related to published works, talks and presentations, Marschak Colloquium, the Milken Institute, and biographical documents and images. It also includes email correspondence that is professional in nature, including correspondence between colleagues at UCLA, economists, writing partners, publishers and others.
  SERIES CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page. Note request to see born-digital materials in "Special Requests" box.
  - Unprocessed MacBook laptop computer., undated (Box 93)
    Unprocessed Macbook laptop (80 GB)
    The library cannot provide access to the files contained in the Macbook laptop due to lack of required hardware. For more information, please contact the reference desk.
  - PC hard drive files, 2004-2008 (Laptop Reading Room laptop)
    0.019 GB (39 digital files) of drafts and final versions of articles, talks, and published works; presentation slides; course materials, biographical materials; administrative materials; and images of Intriligator. Files formats are .pdf/a, .doc, .ppt, and .tif.
    CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page. Note request to see born-digital materials in "Special Requests" box.
  - Email correspondence, 1997-2011 (Laptop Reading Room laptop)
    0.025 GB (2,394 email files) Digital email correspondence files are organized by date and are in mbox file format.
    CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page. Note request to see emails in "Special Requests" box.